[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：现在您注意到当我调用getData函数时，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Now you notice that when I call the getData function,
它没有返回值。
it has no return value.
所以从技术上讲我是在放弃未定义的。
So I'm technically yielding out undefined.
这在这里不会造成问题，因为我们有getData
That doesn't cause a problem here because we have the getData
特意打电话给它。下一个。
wired specifically to call it.next.
但我们可以做出一个实现上的改变，
But there's an implementation change that we can make,
这将重新配置所有这些事情发生的方式。
which is gonna reconfigure the way all of this stuff is happening.
从里面看，它看起来完全一样，但是我们在这里可以观察到的是，
From the inside, it's gonna look exactly the same, but what we can observe here,
这些问题中的一些被问到了，这实际上是一种好的现象
which is actually kind of good that some of these questions were being asked from
聊天。
the chat.
因为我们在这里可以观察到的是我们仍然很容易受到
Because what we can observe here is we're still every bit as susceptible to
像往常一样召回地狱，不是吗？
callback hell as we always were, aren't we?
至少有一件事叫回地狱。
At least one of the things of callback hell.
我们有一个控制反转的问题，不是吗？
We have an inversion of control issue, don't we?
有人可以叫它。下一步，我们没有预料到的方式
Somebody can call it.next in a way that we're not expecting and
把一切都搞砸了。
screw everything up.
我们仍然有一个控制反转的问题。
We still have an inversion of control issue.
我们已经解决了非局部的，非顺序的合理性问题。
We've solved the non-local, non-sequential reasonability issue.
但是我们目前在这个代码库中没有解决方案
But we have no solution currently in this code base for
控制反转回叫地狱问题。
the inversion of control callback hell issue.
猜猜我们要做什么？
So guess what we're gonna do?
我们要把承诺和发电机放在一起。
We're gonna put promises together with generators.
承诺会解决我们的控制反转问题。
Promises are gonna solve our inversion of control issue.
解决我们的信任问题。
Solve our trust issue.
解决我们的流量控制问题。
Solve our flow control control issue.
发电机将解决我们的非局部的，非顺序的合理性问题。
Generators are gonna solve our non-local, non-sequential reasonability issue.
以及对此的关键识别，而不是产生未定义的值，
And the key recognition for this, instead of yielding an undefined value,
我们要把这个连接起来，这样我们就会产生一个承诺。
we're going to wire this up so that we are going to yield a promise.
现在我想让你在我展示给你之前先从概念上考虑一下
Now I want you to think about this conceptually before I show you
任何代码，看着我。
any code, look at me.
在我的代码中，当我说放弃并进行Ajax调用时，
Inside of my code when I say yield and I make an Ajax call,
如果Ajax调用返回我对它的承诺，那么我是否放弃了它的承诺？
if that Ajax call returns me a promise for it, am I yielding out its promise?
是的，那么谁能得到我刚刚做出的承诺
Yes, so who's gonna get the promise that I just yielded
出去？&gt；&gt；Kyle：谁是
out? &gt;&gt; Kyle: Whoever is
用它驱动我的发电机，下一个电话，对吧？
driving my generator with its it.next call, right?
所以想象一下在某个地方有一些管道
So imagine there's some plumbing somewhere which is gonna
在框架或图书馆中。
be in a framework or a library.
但有些地方的管道上写着。下一步，和
But there's some plumbing somewhere that says it.next, and
它得到的是一个承诺。
what it gets back is a promise.
那么这个承诺会有什么用呢？
So what's it gonna do with that promise?
上面写的是承诺然后就是下一个。
It's gonna say promise.then it.next.
这就是它的工作原理。
So here's how this works.
我们给出一个承诺，停顿一下，然后我们说。然后和
We yield out a promise, pausing and then we say .then and
当承诺解决时，我们恢复生成器。
when the promise resolves, we resume the generator.
然后我们让步，暂停，然后继续
And then we yield and pause and then and resume and
让步，暂停，然后继续。
yield and pause and then resume.
这就是我们让魔法发挥作用的方式。
That's how we make that magic work.
这就是我们如何将承诺输入发电机。
That's how we wire promises into the generator.
我们做出承诺，然后承诺恢复生成器，以及何时
We yield out promises and then the promises resume the generator and when
承诺有一些值可以传递，它将它传递给it.next调用。
the promise has some value to pass along, it passes it along to the it.next call.
所以那个管道，我说的那个圆形管道。
So that plumbing, that circular plumbing that I'm talking about.
您可以编写一个实用程序来为您的生成器做到这一点。
You could write a utility to do that for your generators.
它大约有25，30行代码来处理错误处理中的所有细微差别
It's about 25, 30 lines of code to handle all the little nuances in error handling
还有其他的东西。
and all that other stuff.
你可以做到的。
You could do it.
它在我的书里，如果你想写你自己的，你可以看到片断就在那里。
It's in my book, you can see the snippet right there if you want to write your own.
但你不应该这么做。
But you shouldn't have to.
我想让你理解它在做什么的概念。
I want you to understand the concept of what it's doing.
它产生了一个承诺，恢复了一个发电机，产生了一个承诺。
It's yielding out a promise and resuming a generator and yielding out a promise.
我想让你理解这个概念。
I want you to understand that concept.
但对你们每个人来说，去发明自己的驱动程序是不切实际的
But it's not practical for each of you to go invent your own driver for
这些发电机。
these generators.
所以你需要一个内置在图书馆里的
So you're gonna need one that's built into a library and
原来异步有一个，q有一个，co有一个。
it turns out asynquence has one, Q has one, co has one.
我是说，所有主要的图书馆，
I mean, all the major libraries,
他们都有这个，因为他们都知道这是
they all have this, cuz they all know that this is the most
在很长一段时间内，JavaScript编程中的重要模式。
important pattern to land in JavaScript programming in a really long time.
所以他们都有这些司机，我的司机叫Runner。
So they all have these drivers, mine's called runner.
正如您在第8行中看到的，他将生成器传递给了runner方法。
As you see on line 8, he passed the generator to the runner method.
它会自动知道如果你输出一个序列或者
And it automatically knows that if you yield out a sequence or
做出承诺，它就会自动知道等待
yield out a promise, it automatically knows to wait for that and
然后继续，然后等待，然后继续。
then resume and then wait for it and then resume.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：这张幻灯片的要点是
&gt;&gt; Kyle: The main point of this slide is
为了说明异步的价值在于发电机驱动，
to illustrate that the value of asynquence is that a generator driving,
就像我们所说的，实际上只是序列中的一个步骤。
like we're talking about, is really just a step in a sequence.
所以如果我真的需要的话，我可以把它放在另一个序列的中间。
So I can put it right in the middle of another sequence if I really needed to.
这就是为什么在第16行我的序列中还有另一个步骤，它只在
That's why on line 16 I have another step in my sequence that only fires after
发电机已完全完成。
the generator is fully completed.
所以一旦你对异步所提供的抽象进行了思考，
So once you wrap your head around the abstraction that asynquence provides,
序列抽象。
the sequence abstraction.
你序列中的每一步都会成为你想要的任何一步。
Every single step in your sequence becomes whatever you want it to be.
无论是发电机运行，或承诺，或反应序列或
Whether it's a generator run, or a promise, or a reactive sequence or
随便吧。
whatever.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：这就是为什么发电机如此
&gt;&gt; Kyle: This is why generators are so
强大。
powerful.
是的，应该有一些这样的，[声音]什么？
Yeah, should have a few of those, [SOUND] what?
这就是为什么发电机如此强大，因为它们完全改变了游戏规则
This is why generators are so powerful cuz they completely change the game for
我们如何编写异步代码。
how we write our asynchronous code.
还记得上次我们在研讨会开始的时候我说的话吗？
Remember what I said at the very beginning of our workshop last time we were
一起？
together?
我说我们不是在讨论引入新功能，
I said we're not talking about introducing new functionality,
我们在讨论引入新的表现力，为什么？
we're talking about introducing new expressivity, why?
因为当你的大脑不像你的代码那样工作时，就会发生错误
Because bugs happen when your brain doesn't work like the code that you're
写作。
writing.
所以我们试图想出一个模式
So we're trying to come up with a pattern for
编写更接近我们大脑工作的代码。
writing code that works more closely like our brains work.
你知道为什么这比我们说的回调地狱要好得多吗？
Do you see why this is so much better than the callback hell that we've talked about
或者甚至承诺链或者thunk筑巢之类的？
or even the promise chains or the thunk nesting or whatever?
这是好得多，因为它的工作方式，我们的大脑工作。
This is so much better because it works the way our brains work.
因为我们编织着承诺，我们得到了所有的可信性
And because we weave in promises, we get all the trustability
缺乏控制反转，所有的东西都修好了。
the lack of inversion of control, all that stuff's fixed.
所以我们把这两个放在一起，我们最终得到了一个解决方案，一个回叫地狱。
So we put those two together and we get, finally, a solution a callback hell.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：现在，这个模式是这样的
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Now, this pattern is so
重要的是，他们已经提出了一个几乎可以肯定的提案。
important that they've already advanced a proposal that's a virtual certainty.
他们提出了创建下一版本JavaScript的建议
They've advanced a proposal for the next version of JavaScript to create
另一种新类型的函数，称为异步函数。
another new type of function, called an async function.
这和我刚才给你看的完全一样，但是
That does exactly what I just showed you, but
没有任何图书馆需要驱动它。
without any library needing to drive it.
这就是它的样子。&gt；&gt；Kyle：而不是
Here's what it's gonna look like. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Instead of
有类似ASQ().runner的东西，并传入您的生成器，
having something like ASQ().runner, and passing in your generator,
然后做一堆生成Ajax(.)像这样的电话。
and then doing a bunch of yield ajax(..) calls like that.
这就是现在起作用的，因为你有一个可以做所有管道的库
That's what works now cuz you have a library that will do all the plumbing
为了你。
for you.
这个新的提议说，除掉图书馆，
This new proposal says, take out the library,
只需创建一个异步函数，
just make an asynchronous function,
&gt；&gt；Kyle：比如说，就叫它foo吧。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Like call it foo, for example.
打电话给阿福。
And just call foo.
现在我们用等待而不是屈服。
And now we use await instead of yield.
这里有人有C#的经验吗？
Anybody in here have experience with C#?
C#程序员，如果你正在监听，你会发现异步正在等待。
C# programmers, if you're listening in, you'll recognize the async await.
这完全是C#的异步等待。
This is exactly async await from C#.
我们正在将其编码为JavaScript。
We're codifying it into JavaScript.
所以这就是我所说的模式，关于做出承诺，并且
So it's exactly that pattern that I talked about, about yielding a promise out, and
恢复发电机。
resuming the generator.
我们刚刚谈到的那个旧的概念模型。
That old conceptual model that we just talked about.
但是现在，我们甚至不需要一个库，我们可以直接用语法来表达它。
But now, we don't even need a library, we can just express it directly with syntax.
&GT；&GT；Kyle：我100%确信，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: I'm 100% convinced,
这是新的基线
this is the new baseline for
了解如何用JavaScript编写异步代码。
understanding how to write asynchronous code in JavaScript.
这就是我们都要去的地方。
This is where we all have to get to.
我说我们最后一次在一起。
I said the last time we were together.
你不能从车间里得到任何东西，
You don't get anything else out of the workshop,
你必须到达这一点，因为这是新的基线。
you gotta get to this point cuz it's the new baseline.
这是一个新水平的能力，我们都必须围绕着我们的大脑和
It's the new level of competency that we all have to wrap our brains around and
一夜之间就会这样吗？
is it gonna come like that overnight?
不，这需要一些练习和工作。
No, it's gonna take some practice and some work.
但现在好多了，真的
But it's just so much better, it's so
与我们一直在做的相比，游戏规则发生了变化。
game changing compared to what we've been doing all along.
但是它的价值，我希望它的价值是显而易见的，
But the value, I hope the value is evident,
价值应该是值得的。凯尔：什么事？
the value should be clearly worth it. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Yes?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：他们在问
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: They're asking about
转置代码中生成器的质量和速度，
the quality and speed of generators in transpiled code,
&gt；&gt；Kyle：[笑]
&gt;&gt; Kyle: [LAUGH]
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：真的很慢吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Is it really slow?
&gt；&gt；Kyle：[laugh]转换代码不是
&gt;&gt; Kyle: [LAUGH] Transpiled code is not
很棒的代码。
great code.
但是拼写代码并不差
But transpiled code is no worse and
往往比所有真正糟糕的代码都要好
often better than all the really crappy code
你已经写了20年了
that you've been writing for 20 years.
那么拼写的代码是好的吗？
So is the transpiled code good?
它不像ES6那么好，但它可能至少和ES6一样好，如果不是更好的话，
It's not as good as ES6, but it's probably at least as good, if not much better,
而不是你自己写的东西。
than the stuff that you would have written yourself.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：是否有多填充
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Is there a polyfill for
异步等待？&gt；&gt；Kyle：这些是语法，所以
async in await? &gt;&gt; Kyle: These are syntax, so
它们不是聚填材料，它们是易位的。
they're not polyfill, they're transpiled.
Babel支持ES7异步等待。
Babel does support ES7 async await.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：就像一个快速附注。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Just as a quick side note.
我喜欢异步等待语法。
I like the async await syntax.
我喜欢这个的非图书馆版本。
I like the non-library version of this.
因为任何时候我们都可以在没有图书馆的情况下做一些本土化的事情。
Because any time we can do something natively without a library.
耶，太棒了。
Yay, that's awesome.
但是对于异步函数，您应该注意一些注意事项
But there are some caveats that you should be aware of with async functions
发电机不是这样的。
that are not true of generators.
所以它不仅仅是句法上的糖。
So it's not just syntactic sugar.
主要的事情之一，你记得我们之前谈到了可取消的承诺，
One of the major things, you member we talked about cancelable promises earlier,
我说我不是他们的超级粉丝？
and I said I'm not a big fan of them?
这就是它们的来源，因为我们要制作异步函数，
Here's where they come from because we're gonna make async functions,
Foo，当我们调用异步函数时，
foo, when we call an async function,
它将返回给我们一个承诺，让我们知道该函数何时完成。
it's gonna return us a promise that lets us know when that function finishes.
Async函数产生一个承诺，当Async函数
An async function produces a promise that gets resolved when the async function
完成了，对吧？
finishes, right?
但这里有个问题，如果异步函数正在运行并且
But here's the problem, what if that async function is running and
然后其他一些外部影响说我需要中止。
then some other external influence says I need to abort.
我需要取消它正在做的任何事情。
I need to cancel whatever it's doing.
也许异步功能正在使一些真正资源密集型的长时间运行
Maybe the asynch function is making some really resource intensive long running
Ajax调用和下载大量记录，并且在您的
Ajax call and downloading lots of records and something else happens in your
应用程序，你不想再发生这种事了。
application and you don't want that to happen any more.
从外部世界来看，如何取消正在运行的异步
From the outside world, how do you cancel a running async
功能？&gt；&gt；Kyle：答案是你不能。
function? &gt;&gt; Kyle: The answer is you can't.
正在运行的异步函数上没有Cancel方法。
There is no cancel method on a running async function.
你知道他们想做什么吗？
So you know what they want to do?
他们想做出从异步函数中返回的承诺，
They wanna make the promise that comes back from an async function,
可取消的承诺，以便您可以取消承诺。
a cancellable promise so that you can cancel the promise.
这将神奇地将取消消息发送到异步函数中。
And that will send the cancellation message magically into the async function.
在我看来，这是一个难以置信、荒谬、愚蠢的想法。
This is an unbelievably, ridiculously, stupid idea, in my opinion.
它们应该让异步函数返回允许您控制它的其他内容
They ought to have async functions return something else that lets you control it
听从诺言。
and listen to the promise.
我认为他们想出的主意很糟糕，但是
I think it's a terrible idea what they've come up with but
这几乎肯定会发生。
that's what's almost certainly gonna happen.
生成器不会遇到这样的问题，因为生成器不会返回承诺，
Generators don't suffer that problem cuz generators don't return promises,
生成器返回迭代器。
generators return iterators.
迭代器给你控制权。
Iterators give you control.
我给你看了下一个但是
I showed you the .next but
还有一个.return，它将在运行中止一个生成器。
there's also a .return which will abort a generator in mid run.
还有一个.throp，它可以手动将错误发送到生成器中。
And there's a .throw, which can manually send an error into a generator.
因此，生成器提供了比异步函数更多的外部控制。
So generators give you more control from the outside than async functions do.
正是因为这个原因，
It is for that reason,
就我个人而言，我可能大部分时间都会继续使用发电机。
personally, I'm probably gonna keep using generators most of the time.
每隔一段时间，如果有一个真正轻量级的异步进程，我
Every once in a while if there's a really lightweight asynchronous process that I
不关心任何外部控制，我可能会使用异步函数。
don't care about any external control, I'll probably use an async function.
但大多数时候我可能会继续使用发电机。
But most of the time I'm probably gonna keep using generators.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：这是我自己的观点，因为我没有
&gt;&gt; Kyle: It's my own take because I don't
认为取消是一件重要的事情，很多时候。
think cancellation is an important thing, a lot of times.
我认为这个设计没有恰当地考虑到这一点。
And I don't think this design has properly taken that into account.
所以，这是我个人对它的一点看法，但要回到我们曾经的样子
So that's my own little personal take on it but to circle back to what we've been
带着不同的语气谈论。&gt；&gt；Kyle：我给你看过了
talking about with asynquence. &gt;&gt; Kyle: I showed you that
你可以通过发电机。
you could pass in a generator.
你猜怎么着，你也可以传入一个异步函数。
Guess what, you can also pass in an async function.
所以，如果你真的想要改变，你可以这样做，如果你想，这是完全好的。
So if you did want to change, you can do that if you want, it's totally fine.
Asynquence知道如何处理异步函数，就像它知道的一样
Asynquence knows how to handle an asynchronous function just like it knows
如何操作发电机。
how to handle a generator.